MUSTAPHA LATEB

Site: mlateb.github.io

Email: mustapha.lateb@gmail.com

Adress: Chania, Greece Phone: 699 499 7057

INTRODUCTION

I use Satellite Remote Sensing and GIS, Image processing, Machine Learning, Statistics, Timeseries Analysis in order to solve Ecolocal issues, mainly Landcover change and Forestfire mapping. Focuse is on Open Source solutions, Python geospatial libraries, QGIS, linux, Version controle systems. Commercial tools are also used.

I'm currently working as researcher at Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania MAICh.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Researcher at the *Geoinformation in Environmental Management* departement, *Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania MAICh*.

COMMUNICATION AND ORGANISATION

Used to work in multicultural and multidisciplinary teams. Open to new ideas and challenges. I was in the organising committee of the following conferences:

- 38th Annual EARSeL Symposium
- 11th EARSeL Forest Fires SIG Workshop

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

During two years I worked

- Mar 2013-Sep 2013: Energy Steward at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria
- Nov 2011-Feb 2013: Quality Assurance Technician at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria

Novo Nordisk A/S - Global healthcare company headquartered in Denmark.

EDUCATION

- 2016 current : *PhD student*, **Geoinformation applied to Plant Ecology**, UMMTO, Algeria *Topic:* Multitemporal landcover mapping
- 2013 2016 : M. Sc. Degree (2 years), Geoinformation in Environmental Management, MAICh, Greece
 - Thesis topic: "Development of an object-based classification model for monitoring treeline shifting, using aerial photography"
- 2011-2014: Magister degree (2 years), Applied Plant Ecology and Environmental Management, UMMTO, Algeria Thesis topic: "Study of oak hybridisation using Geometric Morphometric (Landmark Method)"
- 2006 2011 : *Ingénieur d'Etat (5 years)*, **Plant ecology and Environment** UMMTO, Algeria *Thesis topic:* "Inventory of oak gallings and evaluation their impact on forest stands"
- 2008 2011 : Senior Technician (3 years), Database Management INSFP, Algeria

Thesis topic: "Creation of a Dynamic Website"

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Geospatial processing: Python (rasterio, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, geopandas, shapely, ...)

Database: SQL

Version controle: Git, GitHub

Web design: HTML , CSS , $\mathsf{Markdown}$

Softwares: QGIS, eCognition, ArcGIS, ERDAS, MapInfo

Operating systems: Linux & Windows

LANGUAGES

• Kabyle : Mother tongue

English: Fluent
French: Fluent
Arabic: Fluent
Greek: Beginner